<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UKMac.net</title><link>https://ukmac.net/</link><description>Recent content on UKMac.net</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ukmac.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Will Green - BritishMac</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/will-green/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/will-green/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://ukmac.net/p/will-green/britishmac.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Will Green - BritishMac" />&lt;p>A couple of weeks ago I got a text out of the blue from an old friend, James who had just heard that another friend of ours, Will Green, had unfortunately passed away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard from Will or spoken to him in some time but the out of the blue call from James did leave me winded. James and I spoke for quite a while, reminiscing about things and I think both of us could not quite believe it. Our friendship came about through our love of Apple Mac computers and a strange coincidence of geography.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My interest in Macs started when I bought an 17&amp;quot; G5 iMac in 2005. At the time my work life was entirely Windows centric and I think I recall deciding to buy a Mac mostly out of curiosity. I was of course quickly sold by the elegance, slick design and polished software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ukmac.net/images/2023-08-05-will-green/DSCF0118.jpeg"
loading="lazy"
alt="iMac G5"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think soon after I bought into the Mac lifestyle I registered this domain (ukmac.net) and started with my early blog focused on Apple and my new Mac. As a keen Apple fan I of course started consuming what I could from the Internet from various web sites/blogs and also from a number of podcasts such as Macbreak Weekly and the wildly eccentric BritishMac podcast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BritishMac was a regular chart topper in the podcast Tech charts in those days and by a bizarre twist of fate was run by Will who happened to live only a few miles from me in Ironbridge, Shropshire. Through another weird coincidence I came into contact with James who had also recently started a Mac focused blog at Ukmac.co.uk, even more coincidently James lived in Broseley a few miles away from Ironbridge in the opposite direction from myself. It was meant to be I guess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suffice to say James, Will and myself ended up meeting in Ironbridge for a few beers and to talk about our favourite subject, Macs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Will was one of life&amp;rsquo;s characters. If you ever heard any of his podcast episodes you will know what I mean. His blog and podcast were unique and eccentric, there really weren&amp;rsquo;t any like it at the time (nor since that I have seen at least). In addition to his irregular podcast postings Will used to host a Christmas get together in Ironbridge and would invite any of his listeners who wished to meet up for drinks and a curry at his local Indian restaurant, the Aftab.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On a couple of these meet-ups Will got us together at a little studio he had at the time to record a podcast episode before we headed to town for food. The resulting recordings were somewhat less than polished but that wasn&amp;rsquo;t the point and didn&amp;rsquo;t stop everyone enjoying being part of the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Will&amp;rsquo;s funeral was this Tuesday in Shrewsbury and I was fully intending to go to show my respects and also to meet-up with some of the group that used to go to Will&amp;rsquo;s Christmas events but in a cruel twist I have been laid up in bed all week with a viral illness and was not able to make it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>14 Peaks Nothing is Impossible</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/14-peaks-nothing-is-impossible/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/14-peaks-nothing-is-impossible/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://ukmac.net/p/14-peaks-nothing-is-impossible/14peaks.jpg" alt="Featured image of post 14 Peaks Nothing is Impossible" />&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.netflix.com/watch/81464765?trackId=255824129&amp;amp;tctx=0%2C0%2C21b04b24-e5f9-494e-be88-808ac95de1b5-232221908%2C21b04b24-e5f9-494e-be88-808ac95de1b5-232221908%7C2%2Cunknown%2C%2C%2CtitlesResults%2C81464765%2CVideo%3A81464765%2CdetailsPagePlayButton" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>14 Peaks: Nothing is Impossible&lt;/a> is a fascinating documentary about a group of Nepalese mountaineers led by the fearless Nirmal Purja who set out to conquer all 14 of the worlds 8,000+ metre mountains in under 7 months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A staggering watch, well recommended. Watch out for the summit of Everest&amp;hellip; Mind blowing&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Been a while</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/been-a-while/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/been-a-while/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://ukmac.net/img/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Been a while" />&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted here for a long time now. Life is busy, work is busy, there are distractions&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week has been a bit crappy to be honest. I have spent most of it lay in bed, coughing and feeling weak and exhausted. My chest hurts and my head feels like its full of cotton wool and I am actually really tired of feeling this way. It&amp;rsquo;s only a week, nothing compared to what some people have to endure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of this week I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt up to doing much at all, I have watched a couple of films which is a bit of a first, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t watched a full film for a long time either. The rest of the time I have been trying to avoid looking at my work inbox/Teams because I know that I would (and did on Tuesday) get drawn into it and hours would quickly pass before I realised that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t doing as I have been told and resting but instead would have been getting stressed about the build up of &amp;ldquo;stuff&amp;rdquo; that I am going to have to deal with when I return to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This has left the remaining time to browse news sites and lurk on Mastodon, both activities that don&amp;rsquo;t do much to cheer you up. Doom, gloom and bad news&amp;hellip; Just now I ended on a link to a YouTube video by Cal Newport titled &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m6AF_aFuD8w" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>The Perks of Living Without Social Media&lt;/a>. In it Cal explains how he has never had social media accounts and the various benefits of living without social media (conveniently side stepping the fact that as a YouTuber he is very much using social media for his job, but we will let that one slide for now). It did make me think though and I realised although I haven&amp;rsquo;t got a Facebook account and deleted my Twitter account after Elon took that service down the toilet I still spend a lot of my time reading what others have to say either on news sites, Mastodon or YouTube. And its true there is a lot there that its better not to know or at least better not to let get into your head and affect your mood and how you think about things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess there is a fine balance between keeping informed and letting the enormous deluge of information available to us all become overwhelming.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I also realised this week is that when I am not working or thinking about work I don&amp;rsquo;t really have an interest or passion that I can spend my spare time on to help me to avoid doom scrolling. I guess this is how I ended up here writing this missive. Journalling is known to be good for helping to focus the mind and I have always thought that I would like to be able to regularly update this blog but never really manage to maintain any sort of inertia (if you look back at other posts on this site you will see what I mean).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway the first task was to fix the site which I managed to break back in April while trying to change this blog from &lt;a class="link" href="https://gohugo.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Hugo&lt;/a> to &lt;a class="link" href="https://tina.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Tina CMS&lt;/a>. After a little fiddling around I managed to restore the previous &amp;ldquo;Deploy Hugo to gh-pages&amp;rdquo; workflow to working order and we are now back up and running.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second step is to start updating here&amp;hellip; Lets see if I can manage to do that&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resetting Apple’s Magic Keyboard and Magic Trackpad</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/resetting-apples-magic-keyboard-and-magic-trackpad/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/resetting-apples-magic-keyboard-and-magic-trackpad/</guid><description>&lt;p>My Magic Keyboard and Magic Trackpad have been gathering dust in the office recently after I changed from using my MacBook in clamshell mode connected to an external monitor to using in front of the monitor, so I decided to setup them up on my iPad Mini. Trouble is they were paired to my MacBook so didn’t show up in Bluetooth settings on the iPad to pair them and I couldn’t remember how to reset them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The solution for this was quite easy. Just power each device on and off five times, then go to the Bluetooth settings on the iPad and they appear ready for pairing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Managing Trackpad on MacOS when using external mouse</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/managing-trackpad-on-macos-when-using-external-mouse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/managing-trackpad-on-macos-when-using-external-mouse/</guid><description>&lt;p>Following my desk space re-organisation this weekend I am back to using my MacBook keyboard again for the first time in quite a while. Having worked predominantly with an external mouse and keyboard with my MacBook in clamshell mode in a vertical stand I decided I would like to disable the MacBook trackpad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simple you would think? Apple do kindly offer a setting in the Mouse &amp;amp; Trackpad Accessibility preferences to do this very thing, however after switching on the option I found my trackpad was still fully operation even with my Logitech MX Master connected. It appears that Bluetooth mice don&amp;rsquo;t register as a mouse being present?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ukmac.net/p/managing-trackpad-on-macos-when-using-external-mouse/mouseoptions.png"
width="827"
height="737"
srcset="https://ukmac.net/p/managing-trackpad-on-macos-when-using-external-mouse/mouseoptions_hu0952fa0ef85f22bbb14187f3ba85ebcb_211784_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://ukmac.net/p/managing-trackpad-on-macos-when-using-external-mouse/mouseoptions_hu0952fa0ef85f22bbb14187f3ba85ebcb_211784_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Disabling trackpad when mouse present"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="112"
data-flex-basis="269px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fix I discovered was to use another Accessibility preference known as Mouse Keys, a legacy service designed to allow cursor control using the keyboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Firstly enable Mouse Keys by switching on the slider in the Pointer Control options, then click on the i next to the slider to reveal the additional preferences dialog below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ukmac.net/p/managing-trackpad-on-macos-when-using-external-mouse/mousekeys.png"
width="827"
height="737"
srcset="https://ukmac.net/p/managing-trackpad-on-macos-when-using-external-mouse/mousekeys_hu0952fa0ef85f22bbb14187f3ba85ebcb_247936_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://ukmac.net/p/managing-trackpad-on-macos-when-using-external-mouse/mousekeys_hu0952fa0ef85f22bbb14187f3ba85ebcb_247936_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Enable mouse keys"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="112"
data-flex-basis="269px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Switch on the two sliders to disable the trackpad when Mouse Keys is on and also enable the option to quickly enable/disable Mouse Keys by pressing the Option key 5 times. You should find that the trackpad is now correctly disabled. To enable the trackpad again just turn off Mouse Keys by tapping Option key 5 times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Job done.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Desk layout</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/new-desk-layout/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/new-desk-layout/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sunday afternoon office tidy&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ukmac.net/p/new-desk-layout/img_0615.jpeg"
width="4032"
height="3024"
srcset="https://ukmac.net/p/new-desk-layout/img_0615_hub6ec13c39cedcecfcc2b6a578f96bc33_2768503_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://ukmac.net/p/new-desk-layout/img_0615_hub6ec13c39cedcecfcc2b6a578f96bc33_2768503_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="My new desk setup"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pre-Xmas Post</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/pre-xmas-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/pre-xmas-post/</guid><description>&lt;p>So its Christmas eve-eve and nearly the end of 2022. Six months into the new job and things are starting to get pretty busy and I am certainly past the honeymoon period and into the time when people around the organisation know who I am. That&amp;rsquo;s both nice but also means free time to develop knowledge and do things how you would ideally want to do them starts to become a rarity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My home office has recently changed layout again and I am back to working entirely on the Samsung M7 screen with my MacBook Pro configured in clamshell mode alongside it. With the upgrade to iOS 16/macOS Ventura bringing &lt;a class="link" href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT213244" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Continuity Camera&lt;/a> support I have been using my iPhone as a replacement for the MacBook webcam and I have to say it works remarkably well, I have had no glitches/disconnects during use with Teams calls in many short and long meetings. My main issue has been finding a way to attach the iPhone at the top of the screen so I appear to be looking in the right direction. I have a fairly dodgy setup at the moment as I haven&amp;rsquo;t found the ideal tool to do this. I have attached a small L bracket to the VESA mounting on the back of the monitor and am then using a small tripod clamp around the iPhone to give it the necessary width and height to raise the camera above the top of the monitor. It works but is not ideal and I will have to try to rig something a bit more substantial in the New Year. There is definitely a market for a nice solution here, most of the stuff available is designed for MagSafe connectors ( my iPhone 11 doesn&amp;rsquo;t have MagSafe ) and for attachment by sticky pads.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If anyone has a good solution for this I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="daily-links">Daily Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Link&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT213244" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Continuity Camera&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Apple guide on using Continutiy Camera&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://twit.social/@ukmac" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>My Mastodon Profile&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Try TWiT.social for a friendly and tech centered Mastodon instance&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Feeling grotty and the sun is shining</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/feeling-grotty-and-the-sun-is-shining/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/feeling-grotty-and-the-sun-is-shining/</guid><description>&lt;p>Its been a while since I posted here. Today finds me at home still full of cold after more than a week with a beautiful sunny day outside that would have been perfect for an Autumn bike ride. Gutted and grumpy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s also been three months since I left CVT and therefore six months since I handed in my notice and they still haven&amp;rsquo;t recruited a replacement to my position. The two guys who worked for me have been struggling along and I think are starting to drown under the weight of tickets in the helpdesk and other work that they are now picking up that they didn&amp;rsquo;t previously have to worry about (because I did it). I do really feel for them, they are both nice guys and being left to flounder by the charities management team is really not good. I have continued to offer them support and advice and will continue to do so but what I can do for them isn&amp;rsquo;t a substitute for a permenant IT manager who can take some of the load from them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="daily-links">Daily Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Link&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://twitter.com/merill/status/1578301242530443264?s=20&amp;amp;t=FwmWoB70r6a9_YIKd0p_kQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Azure AD Admin shortcuts&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A very useful list of shortcuts to variety of Azure AD Admin pages&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://music.apple.com/gb/album/logos-live-recorded-live-at-the-dominion-london-1982/724499904" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Tangerine Dream - Logos&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Currently listening to one of my all time favourite TD albums. Powerful memories evoked of this concert at the Odeon in Birmingham&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>New Zwift Hub Smart Trainer Announced</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/new-zwift-hub-smart-trainer-announced/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/new-zwift-hub-smart-trainer-announced/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://ukmac.net/p/new-zwift-hub-smart-trainer-announced/zwifthub.jpg" alt="Featured image of post New Zwift Hub Smart Trainer Announced" />&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://uk.zwift.com/pages/zwift-hub" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>This looks interesting&lt;/a>. The Zwift Hub smart trainer has just been announced and looks like it will be a popular choice as an entry level option for joining the Zwift community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just £449 in the UK with 24 months interest free credit to boot !&lt;/p>
&lt;p>May be tempted myself&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Link&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://uk.zwift.com/pages/zwift-hub" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Zwift Hub&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>£449 for a nice looking direct drive smart trainer&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Archives</title><link>https://ukmac.net/archives/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sweet and Wide...</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/sweet-and-wide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/sweet-and-wide/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://ukmac.net/p/sweet-and-wide/wide.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Sweet and Wide..." />&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/48126477@N05/16616199274" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>&lt;img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7599/16616199274_7509fe9fbf.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Ultrawide Macbook"
>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have looked at these ultra wide screens and have to admit this looks enticing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Links</title><link>https://ukmac.net/links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/links/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://ukmac.net/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>