<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Daily Post on UKMac.net</title><link>https://ukmac.net/tags/daily-post/</link><description>Recent content in Daily Post on UKMac.net</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ukmac.net/tags/daily-post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pre-Xmas Post</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/pre-xmas-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/pre-xmas-post/</guid><description>&lt;p>So its Christmas eve-eve and nearly the end of 2022. Six months into the new job and things are starting to get pretty busy and I am certainly past the honeymoon period and into the time when people around the organisation know who I am. That&amp;rsquo;s both nice but also means free time to develop knowledge and do things how you would ideally want to do them starts to become a rarity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My home office has recently changed layout again and I am back to working entirely on the Samsung M7 screen with my MacBook Pro configured in clamshell mode alongside it. With the upgrade to iOS 16/macOS Ventura bringing &lt;a class="link" href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT213244" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Continuity Camera&lt;/a> support I have been using my iPhone as a replacement for the MacBook webcam and I have to say it works remarkably well, I have had no glitches/disconnects during use with Teams calls in many short and long meetings. My main issue has been finding a way to attach the iPhone at the top of the screen so I appear to be looking in the right direction. I have a fairly dodgy setup at the moment as I haven&amp;rsquo;t found the ideal tool to do this. I have attached a small L bracket to the VESA mounting on the back of the monitor and am then using a small tripod clamp around the iPhone to give it the necessary width and height to raise the camera above the top of the monitor. It works but is not ideal and I will have to try to rig something a bit more substantial in the New Year. There is definitely a market for a nice solution here, most of the stuff available is designed for MagSafe connectors ( my iPhone 11 doesn&amp;rsquo;t have MagSafe ) and for attachment by sticky pads.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If anyone has a good solution for this I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="daily-links">Daily Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Link&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT213244" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Continuity Camera&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Apple guide on using Continutiy Camera&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://twit.social/@ukmac" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>My Mastodon Profile&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Try TWiT.social for a friendly and tech centered Mastodon instance&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Feeling grotty and the sun is shining</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/feeling-grotty-and-the-sun-is-shining/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/feeling-grotty-and-the-sun-is-shining/</guid><description>&lt;p>Its been a while since I posted here. Today finds me at home still full of cold after more than a week with a beautiful sunny day outside that would have been perfect for an Autumn bike ride. Gutted and grumpy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s also been three months since I left CVT and therefore six months since I handed in my notice and they still haven&amp;rsquo;t recruited a replacement to my position. The two guys who worked for me have been struggling along and I think are starting to drown under the weight of tickets in the helpdesk and other work that they are now picking up that they didn&amp;rsquo;t previously have to worry about (because I did it). I do really feel for them, they are both nice guys and being left to flounder by the charities management team is really not good. I have continued to offer them support and advice and will continue to do so but what I can do for them isn&amp;rsquo;t a substitute for a permenant IT manager who can take some of the load from them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="daily-links">Daily Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Link&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://twitter.com/merill/status/1578301242530443264?s=20&amp;amp;t=FwmWoB70r6a9_YIKd0p_kQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Azure AD Admin shortcuts&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A very useful list of shortcuts to variety of Azure AD Admin pages&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://music.apple.com/gb/album/logos-live-recorded-live-at-the-dominion-london-1982/724499904" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Tangerine Dream - Logos&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Currently listening to one of my all time favourite TD albums. Powerful memories evoked of this concert at the Odeon in Birmingham&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item></channel></rss>